A Guide to the Alfred Ezra Mirsky papers, Rockefeller University Faculty FA131
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Manuscript materials, 4
  - Miscellaneous; not A.E. Mirsky; not clearly identified
    - V.G. Allfrey and A.E. Mirsky. On the role of electrical charge on the chemical activity of the cell nucleus, 1959 (Box 33)
      npi (no publication information) (Notation on original folder "Submitted to USSR Institute of Cytology for Nossonov Memorial Feb 15, 1959).
    - V.G. Allfrey and A.E. Mirsky. On the purity and function in isolated cell nuclei, 1959 (Box 33)
      npi (no publication information) Correspondence to Science;.
    - typescript draft (Internal evidence indicates submitted to Science) (Box 33)
    - A.E. Mirsky and V.G. Allfrey. Biochemical activities of the cell nucleus. Diseases of the Nervous System, 1960 (Box 34)
      Monograph supplement, XXI, No. 2, 1-6.
      Galley proof.
    - V.G. Allfrey, J.W. Hopkins, J.H. Frenster and A.E. Mirsky Reactions governing incorporation of amino acids into the proteins of the isolated cell nuclei, 1960 (Box 34)
      Ann N Y Acad Sci 88, 722-740.
    - J.H. Frenster, V.G. Allfrey and A.E. Mirsky In vitro incorporation of amino acids into the proteins of isolated nuclear ribosomes, 1961 (Box 34)
      B and B Acta 47, 130-137.
    - H. Naora, H. Naora, A.E. Mirsky and V.G. Allfrey Magnesium and calcium in isolated cell nuclei, 1961 (Box 34)
      JGP 44, 713-742.
      Galley proofs; typescript drafts; working figures.
    - V.G. Allfrey and A.E. Mirsky. On the supposed contamination of calf thymus nuclei by intact cells, 1961 (Box 34)
    - V.G. Allfrey and A.E. Mirsky. How cells make molecules, 1961 (Box 34)
      Scientific American 205, no. 3, 74-82.
    - A. Sibatani, S.R. deKloet, V.G. Allfrey and A.E. Mirsky. Isolation of a nuclear RNA fraction resembling DNA in its base composition, 1962 (Box 34)
      PNAS 48, 471-477.
    - H. Naora, H. Naora, M. Izawa, V.G. Allfrey and A.E. Mirsky. Some observations on differences in composition between the nucleus and cytoplasm of the frog oocyte, 1962 (Box 34)
      PNAS 48, 853-859.
      Galley proof, typescript draft; negatives of figures; working materials.
      Laboratory notes kept in order in which found.
    - A.E. Mirsky. Book review of "The Biosynthesis of proteins" by H. Chantrenne, 1962 (Box 34)
      J Am Chem Soc 84, 2466.
      Photocopy of review.
    - V.G. Allfrey and A.E. Mirsky. Evidence for the complete DNA-dependence of RNA synthesis in isolated thymus nuclei, 1962 (Box 34)
      PNAS 48, 1590-1596.
      Corrected galley proof; partial typescript draft; correspondence; assorted published papers (not A.E. Mirsky); some handwritten notes.
    - H. Naora, A.E. Mirsky and V.G. Allfrey Some aspects of transport of substances into nucleus from environment, 1962? (Box 34)
      Typescript draft with corrections; mounted photographs with descriptions; working materials.
    - John H. Frenster, 1962-1966 (Box 34)
      (These are the years worked in A.E. Mirsky laboratory) Assorted mss written, submitted and published thru this period: (Information cited from original mss folder).
      1) J.H. Frenster. The interaction of load, capacity and resistance in body processes. (Submitted to American J Medicine).
      2) J.H. Frenster, V.G. Allfrey and A.E. Mirsky In vitro stimulation by DNA of the metabolism of ribosomes from the cell nucleus of lymphocytes. (Short letter submitted to Nature) (no publication information).
      3) J.H. Frenster. Limits to functional hypertrophy in high-output failure.
      (Accepted by Annals of Internal Medicine).
      Typescript drafts of 3 mss.
      - 3) J.H. Frenster. Limits to functional hypertrophy in high-output failure
    - E.H. Davidson, V.G. Allfrey and A.E. Mirsky Gene expression in differentiated cells, 1963 (Box 34)
      PNAS 49, 53-60.
    - E.H. Davidson. Heritability and control of differentiated function in cultured cells, 1963 (Box 34)
      JGP 46, 983-998.
    - B.S. McEwen, V.G. Allfrey and A.E. Mirsky Studies of energy-yielding reactions in thymus nuclei. I. Comparison of nuclear nd mitochondrial phosphorylation, 1963 (Box 34)
      J Biol Chem 238, 758-766.
    - B.S. McEwen, V.G. Allfrey and A.E. Mirsky Studies on energy-yielding reactions in thymus nuclei II. Pathways of aerobic carbohydrate catabolism, 1963 (Box 34)
      J Biol Chem 238, 2571-2578.
    - B.S. McEwen, V.G. Allfrey and A.E. Mirsky Studies on energy-yielding reactions in thymus nuclei. III. Participation of glycolysis and the citric acid cycle in nuclear adenosine triphosphate synthesis, 1963 (Box 34)
      J Biol Chem 238, 2579-2586.
    - V.G. Allfrey, V.C. Littau and A.E. Mirsky. On the role of histones in regulating ribonucleic acid synthesis in the cell nucleus, 1963 (Box 34)
      PNAS 49, 414-421.
    - M. Izawa, V.G. Allfrey and A.E. Mirsky. Composition of the nucleus and chromosomes in the lampbrush stage of the newt oocyte, 1963 (Box 34)
      PNAS 50, 811-817.
      Galley proof; typescript drafts with corrections; negatives of tables; photographs of figures.
    - J.H. Frenster, V.G. Allfrey and A.E. Mirsky Repression and derepression within isolated chromatin of interphase lymphocytes, 1963 (Box 34)
    - A.E. Mirsky. Book review of "The Organization of Cellular Activity" by Ch. M.A. Kuyper, 1963 (Box 34)
      Arch Biochem Biophys 101, 369-370.
      Galley proof; photocopy of review.
    - A.E. Mirsky. The nuclear membrane and nucleocytoplasmic interchange. Preface, 1964 (Box 35)
      Protoplasmotologia v 5, pt 2, pp 1-3.
      Galley proof; printer's copy; typescript drafts; working outline.
    - V.G. Allfrey, R. Faulkner and A.E. Mirsky Acetylation and methylation of histones and their possible role in the regulation of RNA synthesis, 1964 (Box 35)
      PNAS 51, 786-794.
    - V.G. Allfrey, V.C. Littau and A.E. Mirsky Methods for the purification of thymus nuclei and their application to studies of nuclear protein synthesis, 1964 (Box 35)
      J Cell Biol 21, 213-231.
    - V.C. Littau, V.G. Allfrey, J.H. Frenster and A.E. Mirsky. Active and inactive regions of nuclear chromatin as revealed by electron microscope autoradiography. PNAS 52, pp 93-100, 1964; Working typescript draft (Box 35)
    - A.E. Mirsky. Genetics and human affairs. Book review of "Essays of a Humanist" by Sir Julian Huxley, 1964 (Box 35)
      Scientific American 211, no 4, 135-138.
      Assorted background papers; reaction correspondence some forwarded by Scientific American; issue of publication and typescript drafts.
    - A.E. Mirsky. Letter in reply to Sir Julian Huxley, 1965 (Box 35)
      Scientific American 212, no 1, 7-9.
      Typescript drafts with corrections; issue of publication.
    - E.H. Davidson, G.W. Haslet, R.J. Finney, V.G. Allfrey and A.E. Mirsky Evidence for prelocalization of cytoplasmic factors affecting gene activation in early embryogenesis, 1965 (Box 35)
      PNAS 54, 696-704.
    - V.C. Littau, C.J. Burdick, V.G. Allfrey and A.E. Mirsky. The role of histones in the maintenance of chromatin structure, 1965 (Box 35)
      PNAS 54, 1204-1212.
    - [A.O.Pogo] A micro-electrophoretic method for fractionation and quantitative determination of histone, 1966? (Box 35)
      Typescript draft; photographs of figures and electrophoresis work. Name of Pogo appeared only on original ms folder.
    - R. Bachvarova, E.H. Davidson, V.G. Allfrey and A.E. Mirsky. Activation of RNA synthesis associated with gastrulation, 1966 (Box 35)
      PNAS 55, 358-365.
    - B.G.T. Pogo, V.G. Allfrey and A.E. Mirsky RNA synthesis and histone acetylation during the course of gene activation in lymphocytes, 1966 (Box 35)
      PNAS 55, 805-812.
    - L.J. Kleinsmith, V.G. Allfrey and A.E. Mirsky. Phosphoprotein metabolism in isolated lymphocyte nuclei, 1966 (Box 35)
      PNAS 55, 1182-1189.
    - A.O. Pogo, V.G. Allfrey and A.E. Mirsky. Evidence for increased DNA template activity in regenerating liver nuclei, 1966 (Box 35)
      PNAS 56, 550-557.
    - A.E. Mirsky. The discovery of DNA, 1968; 2 folders (Box 35)
      Scientific American 218 no 6, 78-88.
      - untitled (Box 35, Folder 1)
        Background correspondence and photographs; galley proofs of photographs with explanation sheets.
      - untitled (Box 35, Folder 2)
        Assorted background papers; typescript drafts with corrections.
    - A.E. Mirsky, C.J. Burdick, E.H. Davidson and V.C. Littau. The role of lysine-rich histone in the maintenance of chromatin structure in metaphase chromosomes, 1968 (Box 35)
      PNAS 61, 592-597.
      Galley proof; typescript drafts; photographs of figures; background papers; laboratory notes.
    - B.G.T. Pogo, A.O. Pogo, V.G. Allfrey and A.E. Mirsky. Changing patterns of histone acetylation and RNA synthesis in regeneration of the liver, 1968 (Box 36)
      PNAS 59, 1337-1344.
      Correspondence concerning lost reprints.
    - E.H. Davidson, A.E. Mirsky, B.R. Voeller Letter re: Salvador E. Luria, 1969; photocopies of published letter, typescript drafts; photocopies of published letters (Box 36)
      Scientific American 220, no 5, 8-9.
    - A.E. Mirsky. "Biology and the future of Man", Philip Handler (Ed), 1970 (Box 36)
      American 223, 135-137.
      Publisher's typed copy; typescript and handwritten drafts with corrections.
    - A.E. Mirsky. The structure of chromatin, 1971 (Box 36)
      PNAS 68, 2945-2948.
      Correspondence; galley proof; editor's corrected ms; typescript and handwritten drafts with corrections.
    - A.E. Mirsky and B. Silverman. Blocking by histones of accessibility to DNA in chromatin, 1972 (Box 36)
      PNAS 69, 2115-2119.
      Correspondence; galley proof; editor's corrected ms; typescript draft; working draft with background papers.
    - A.E. Mirsky, B. Silverman and N.C. Panda Blocking by histones of accessibility to DNA in chromatin: Addition of histones, 1972 (Box 36)
      PNAS 69, 3243-3246.
      Correspondence; galley proof; typescript draft with background papers.
    - B. Silverman and A.E. Mirsky. The accessibility of DNA in chromatin to DNA polymerase and RNA polymerase, 1973 (Box 36)
      PNAS 70, 1326-1330.
      Correspondence; galley proof; typescript drafts with corrections; working materials.
    - A.E. Mirsky and B. Silverman. The effects of selective extraction of histones on template activities of chromatin by use of exogenous DNA and RNA polymerases, 1973 (Box 36)
      PNAS 70, 1973-1975.
      Correspondence; galley proof; typescript drafts with corrections.
    - B. Silverman and A.E. Mirsky. Addition of histones to histone-depleted nuclei: Effect on template activity toward DNA and RNA polymerases, 1973 (Box 36)
      PNAS 70, 2637-2641.
      Correspondence; galley proof; typescript draft with corrections; working materials with laboratory notes.
  - The Cell edited by Jean Brachet and Alfred E. Mirsky Volumes I thru VI
    - Prospectus (Purpose and Scope) 1956; Reviews 1959-1967; some correspondence (Box 37)
    - Correspondence with Academic Press, 2 folders (Box 37)
      - 1955 December-1959 June
      - 1959 July-1968 April
    - Correspondence: Academic Press with contributors, 1959-1961 (Box 37)
      (carbon copies sent to A.E. Mirsky).
    - Correspondence: J. Brachet and A.E. Mirsky, 3 folders (Box 37)
      - 1955-1957
      - 1958-1960
      - 1961-1968
    - Correspondence with contributors/refusals (Box 37)
      Asked to contribute but refused, or failure to supply ms. on time.
    - Correspondence with contributors, 2 boxes and 8 folders
      Arranged in alphabetical order with indication of volume and chapter; ms when available
      - Robert D. Allen Vol. II, 3 (Box 38, Folder 1)
        Includes ms.
      - Vincent Allfrey Vol. I, 7; ms only (Box 38, Folder 1)
      - Marcel Bessis Vol IV, 10 (Box 38, Folder 1)
      - Robert Briggs and Tom King.Vol. I, Part II, 5 (Box 38, Folder 1)
      - Robert Cordier Vol. VI, 5 (Box 38, Folder 1)
        Includes ms and W.H. Miller comments on Cordier ms.
      - Albert J. Dalton Vol. II, 8 (Box 38, Folder 2)
      - James D. Ebert Vol. I, Part II, 14 (Box 38, Folder 2)
      - Ralph O. Erickson Vol. I, Part II, 12 (Box 38, Folder 2)
      - Maurice Errera Vol. I, Part II, 15 (Box 38, Folder 2)
      - Don W. Fawcett Vol. II, 4 (Box 38, Folder 2)
      - Adrienne Ficq Vol. I, Part I, 3 (Box 38, Folder 2)
      - Sylvia Fitton Jackson Vol. VI, 6 (Box 38, Folder 2)
      - Sylvia Fitton Jackson (cont'd) Vol. VI, 6; final copy of ms (Box 38, Folder 3)
      - Roy P. Forster Vol. V, 2 (Box 38, Folder 3)
      - Louis Gallien Vol. I, Part II, 10 (Box 38, Folder 3)
      - Isidore Gersh Vol. I, Part 1,2 (Box 38, Folder 3)
      - David Glick Vol I, Part I, 5 (Box 38, Folder 3)
      - David Goddard Vol. I, Introduction (Box 38, Folder 3)
      - George Gomori Agreed to submit ms but died (Box 38, Folder 3)
      - Samuel Granick Vol. II, 7 (Box 38, Folder 3)
      - Karl G. Grell Vol. VI, 1; ms only (Box 38, Folder 4)
      - Clifford Grobstein Vol. I, Part II, 11 (Box 38, Folder 4)
      - Jerome Gross Correspondence only, no ms ever received (Box 38, Folder 4)
      - J.B.S. Haldane Correspondence only, no ms ever received (Box 38, Folder 4)
      - H.E. Huxley Vol. IV, 7 (Box 38, Folder 4)
      - Holger Hyden Vol. IV, 5 (Box 38, Folder 4)
      - M.J. Kopac Vol. I, Part I, 6 (Box 38, Folder 4)
      - Elaine LeBreton and Yvonne Moule Vol. V, 8, Part 2; ms only (Box 38, Folder 4)
      - Daniel Mazia Vol. III, 2 (Box 39, Folder 1)
      - William Miller Vol. IV, 6 (Box 39, Folder 1)
      - William Montagna Vol V, 5 (Box 39, Folder 1)
      - David Nanney and Marie A. Rudzinska Vol. IV, 3 (Box 39, Folder 1)
      - Alex B. Novikoff Vol. II, 5 and 6 (Box 39, Folder 1)
        Includes ms for chapter 6.
      - Ch. Oberling and W. Bernard Vol. V, 7 (Box 39, Folder 2)
        Includes bibliography.
      - Eric Ponder Vol II, 1 (Box 39, Folder 2)
        See also Marcel Bessis ms Vol IV, 10.
      - Keith Porter and George Palade Projected plans for chapter (Box 39, Folder 2)
      - Keith Porter Vol. II, 9 (Box 39, Folder 2)
        See also Bruce Voeller ms Vol. VI, 4.
      - John R. Raper and Karl Esser Vol. VI, 3 (Box 39, Folder 2)
      - Marcus M. Rhoades Vol. III, 1 (Box 39, Folder 3)
      - C.F. Robinow Vol. IV, 2 (Box 39, Folder 3)
      - John Runnström, B.E. Hagström and P. Perlmann Vol. I, Part II, 9 (Box 39, Folder 3)
      - René Thomas Vol IV, 1 (Box 39, Folder 4)
      - William Trager Vol VI, 2 (Box 39, Folder 4)
      - Bruce Voeller Vol. VI, 4 (Box 39, Folder 4)
      - P.M.B. Walker and B.M. Richards Vol. I, Part I, 4 (Box 39, Folder 4)
      - Philip R. White Vol. I, Part I, 8 (Box 39, Folder 4)
      - Ralph W.G. Wyckoff Vol. I, Part I, 1 (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - Alfred E. Mirsky and Syozo Osawa chapter in The Cell Vol. II, 10 "The Interphase Nucleus", 2 boxes and 10 folders
      - Correspondence A.E. Mirsky and Academic Press (Box 40, Folder 1)
      - untitled, Typescript and handwritten drafts with corrections (original folder noted "The Cell" Original) (Box 40, Folder 2)
        Typescript and handwritten drafts with corrections (original folder noted "The Cell" Original).
      - untitled (Box 40, Folder 3)
        Typescript draft (original folder noted "first typing").
        Includes S. Osawa note.
      - untitled (Box 40, Folder 4)
        Typescript draft with corrections (original folder noted "Rough draft").
      - References; figure legends; with working and photocopied background material (Box 40, Folder 5)
      - untitled (Box 40, Folder 6)
        Typescript draft (original folder noted "2nd carbon copy").
      - untitled (Box 40, Folder 7)
        Typescript draft with corrections (original folder noted "2nd carbon copy with changes and notations").
      - Original photographs of figures 1 thru 27 (as noted on original envelope) (Box 40, Folder 8)
      - untitled (Box 41, Folder 1)
        Photographs of figures with legends; lack figures 1, 2, 6a, 6b, 16, 18 thru 27; some unidentified photographs.
      - untitled (Box 41, Folder 2)
        3 printer's copies of chapter; 1 with corrections.
      - Miscellaneous The Cell. (Box 41)
        Includes:.
        - Notice and form letters to contributors
        - Vol. I-VI List of contributors, table of contents; photocopied from published volumes
        - Vol. I-V Working materials of outlines of tables of contents and contributors
        - Vol. VI Galley proofs of author and subject index, table of contents, list of contributors; working materials
        - Publisher's advertising leaflets
    - New Edition (Tentative) The Cell (Box 41)
      Outline drawn up on/about Feb 25, 1965; Correspondence 1967-1969 with prospective contributors concerning consideration of new edition, then letter of cancellation.
- Conferences, meetings, seminars, 1951-1962; 5
  Consist of correspondence; programs; memorabilia; mss with working materials in some instances; outlines; abstracts; some correspondence about cancellations because of illness; in some instances information is sketchy and inconclusive.
  Refusals 1951-1962 (later in boxes 5-15).
  - Cold Spring Harbor Symp Quant Biol XII, 1947 (Box 42)
    Mirsky "Chemical properties of isolated chromosomes".
    Typescript and handwritten drafts.
  - The Harvey Lecture Series 46, NYC Mirsky "The chemical composition of chromosomes", 1951 June (Box 42)
    Correspondence with Eichna; galley proofs; published ms; typescript and handwritten drafts.
    Laboratory notes on "Regenerating Liver" kept in order in which found.
  - Cold Spring Harbor Symp Quant Biol XVI. Mirsky "Some enzymes of isolated nuclei", 1951 (Box 42)
    Correspondence with Warren includes answer to Ephrussi comment; typescript draft.
  - St. Louis, Mo. Botanical Garden Conference. Mirsky on the composition of the cell, 1951 November 8-9 (Box 42)
    Correspondence with E. Anderson.
  - Fieldston School, N Y C (3 talks) (Box 42)
    - Mirsky talk at the Dr. Kelly Lectures, 1952 January 9
      Correspondence with Darby; Dec 10, 1951 correspondence indicates A.E. Mirsky gave talk previous year.
    - Federation of Science Teachers Assoc Meeting. Mirsky on biochemical research techniques, 1953 March 28
      Correspondence with Darby.
    - Mirsky "Communication of information within the living cell", 1961 April
      Handwritten outline.
  - Cold Spring Harbor Symp XVII on The Neuron, 1952 June 6-13 (Box 42)
    Mirsky holographs concerning symposium planning; miscellaneous correspondence.
  - Utrecht, Netherlands Symposium on The biochemical and structural basis of morphogenesis, 1952 August 27-29 (Box 42)
    List of participants; programs; copy of proceedings. Aug 30-31 private meeting.
  - Stockholm Conference on Cellular basis of differentiation, 1952 September 2-6 (Box 42)
    List of active Swedish participants; skeleton program.
  - Yale University Experimental Embryology Seminar, 1953 April 11 (Box 42)
    Mirsky presented thoughts on protein differentiation during development.
    Correspondence.
  - Bellagio, Italy 9th International Congress of Genetics, 1953 August 24-31 (Box 42)
    Mirsky "Genetics and cell physiology in studies of cell nucleus" Aug 26.
    Correspondence; A.E. Mirsky chairman special session "Cell Physiology" Aug 25.
  - Dartmouth College Scientific Assoc, 1954 March (Box 42)
  - Atlantic City, N.J. Histochemical Society Symposium on The basophilic components of the cytoplasm, 1954 April 16 (Box 42)
    Mirsky "Ribonucleoprotein and protein synthesis" Correspondence; printer's copy and typescript drafts with corrections.
  - Cold Spring Harbor, Long Island Biological Assoc Seminar, 1955 April 13 (Box 42)
    Mirsky "Some observations on chemical activities in the cell nucleus".
  - Wesleyan University, Sigma Xi Lecture, 1955 April 14 (Box 42)
    Mirsky "Chemistry of the cell nucleus".
  - Brussels 3rd International Congress of Biochemistry, 1955 August 1-6 (Box 42)
    Mirsky "Some biochemical aspects of the cell nucleus".
    Correspondence; galley proof with figures.
  - WNYC Science Seminar, NYC, 1956 January 9 (Box 42)
    Mirsky biology report.
    Correspondence; typescript drafts with corrections.
  - Duke University School of Medicine, 1956 January 18 (Box 42)
    Mirsky "Some biochemical activities of the cell nucleus".
  - Gordon Research Conf AAAS, New Hampton, NH, 1956 June 25-29 (Box 42)
    Mirsky and Allfrey "Nucleoprotein systems of the cell nucleus".
    Correspondence; programs.
  - Cold Spring Harbor Symp Quant Biol XXI on Genetic mechanism - structure and function, 1956 June 4-12 (Box 42)
    Mirsky, Osawa, Allfrey "The nucleus as a site of biochemical activity".
    Correspondence; typescript drafts of references.
  - McCollum-Pratt Symposium on The chemical basis of heredity, 1956 June 19-22 (Box 42)
    Allfrey, Mirsky, Osawa "The nucleus and protein synthesis".
    Reprint.
  - Moscow-International Symposium on the Origin of life on earth, 1957 August 19-24 (Box 42)
    Mirsky "A note on the evolution of nucleic acid" Galley proof; correspondence; 1958 Oct 17 followed up by research evaluation meeting at Berkeley of the American participants of Moscow Symposium.
  - St. Andrews, Scotland - IX International Congress for Cell Biology, 1957 August 28-September 3 (Box 42)
    Mirsky and Allfrey paper concerning the cell nucleus.
    Correspondence; paper presented by Allfrey.
  - Albert Einstein College of Medicine to discuss problems of mutual interest relating to lymphoid tissue and the hematopoietic system, 1957 December 13 (Box 42)
    Mirsky "Synthetic activities of isolated lymphocytic nuclei".
  - Stuyvesant High School. Arranged by Bell Telephone Laboratories with NYC Bd of Education. Lecture to high school science students, 1958 March 14 (Box 42)
    Mirsky "The chemistry of the cell nucleus".
  - McCollum-Pratt Symposium on The chemical basis of development, 1958 March 24-27 (Box 42)
    Mirsky and Allfrey "The role of the cell nucleus in development".
    Typescript and handwritten drafts; revised typescript and handwritten drafts of discussion.
  - University of Texas Special Lectures for 75th Anniversary, 1958 March 31-April 3 (Box 42)
    Mirsky "Some chemical aspects of the cell nucleus".
    Programs.
  - Brussels Symposium on the Physiological relationship between nucleus and cytoplasm; organized by International Society of Cell Biology, 1958 June 9-13 (Box 42)
    Mirsky and Allfrey "Differentiation considered with reference to the relationship between nucleus and cytoplasm".
  - Englewood, N.J. Adult School of Englewodd Course Science Today. Mirsky "Biology", 1958 November 25 (Box 42)
    Correspondence; program.
  - Arden House Conference on Nutrition. Mirsky "Some nutritional aspects of animal cell structure", 1958 December 13-16 (Box 42)
    Correspondence; programs; list of participants and summary of each participants talk.
  - New York Hospital Pathology Society Seminars, 1959 January 14 (Box 42)
    Mirsky "Synthesis in the cell nucleus".
  - Oklahoma State University, 1959 February 24 (Box 42)
    Correspondence; itinerary; cancelled because of illness.
  - University of Texas M.D. Anderson Hospital and Tumor Institute Annual Symposium on Fundamental cancer research - genetics and neoplastic growth, 1959 February 26 (Box 42)
    Mirsky "Macromolecular synthesis and gene function".
    Correspondence; itinerary; program; cancelled because of illness.
  - Tulane University Graugnard Lecture, 1959 February 27 (Box 42)
    Mirsky "The cell nucleus".
    Correspondence; itinerary; cancelled due to illness.
  - Washington, DC 96th Annual meeting of National Academy of Sciences, 1959 April 27-29 (Box 43)
    Indication Mirsky attended but no evidence of paper presentation.
    Programs; abstracts of papers presented; duplicated material.